Friend, we have been making videos on health insurance for the last
four-five years.  And
we have compared health insurance policies on various
parameters like claim settlement ratio and
claim ratio.
And we have observed that there are only five or six
companies which after some hard work reach the top.
HDFC Ago, Niva, Bua, Ah C's
Supreme, Aditya Birla, Bajaj Allians and
ICICI Lobert.  And just 6-7 months ago
we had done the analysis.  Even then these companies had
come to the top after some hard work.  So, in this
video we're going to take a step further and we're
going to dissect these companies and their top
plans.  So that by the end of the video you
get complete clarity about which policy you should
take.  First of all, let us look at the maximum
cover and eligibility of all these policies.
Also, we will talk about the top plans of all these companies.
Like HDFC's
Optimum Secure, Kar's Care Supreme and so
on.  The maximum age to enter ICICI Lambar
is 65.  That means you
can enter this policy anytime before this.  Minimum age
is 6 years which is very interesting.  But the
thing to note here is that this is
a part of a family plan.  Also
with ICICI you can get unlimited cover
more on that later.  Apart from ICICI, there
is no restriction on maximum age to enter in all other policies.  So,
if you have parents who do
not have a policy and are above 65 years of age, then
these are some decent options available to you.  I would also like to mention one thing that
till
2024 the maximum age cap was of 65 on HDFC,
Bajaj, Elan and Niva, but
after that this restriction was removed.  So right now there is no
maximum age to enter
in these policies.  Talking about max cover,
here Bajaj Alan is offering the lowest
cover which is 50 lakhs.  All other policies are
giving you a cover of Rs 1 to 2 crore.
Apart from this, your limit in ICICI
is Rs 10 crore and unlimited cover but just
because someone is offering you so much cover, it is
not necessary that you have to take it.  Room rent is also
one of the most important parameters in
comparing this policy.  But if
room rent is charged in any policy or plan
or there is a limit on room rent, then
we totally reject it without thinking.
But as you can see here, there is
no limit on room rent in any of the policies.  In ICICI
you cannot just take a sweet room which is
still acceptable.  Now let us see
what is special in these policies.  Basically why should you
consider these policies.
With HDFC Ago, you get two times cover from day one which can also
go up to three
times.  That means if you have a cover of Rs 50 lakh,
you will get up to Rs 1.5 crore.
In this you also get one time registration benefit.
Basically, if you claim the cover of Rs 50 lakh and
spend it,
you will get the same amount of cover.
So basically you get a total of four times
cover.  I would also like to mention
one thing that HDFC has in store for you is its
Optima Super Secure plan which offers
four times cover and one time
registration benefit.  So in total
you get five times cover.
Obviously its premium is a little higher.
And since it is a three year policy,
you will have to pay the entire amount for three years
in one go during renewal.
But if you can pay a little
extra premium you will get extra
cover.  You can get up to five times cover at K Supreme.
Basically this is
like a cumulative bonus.  This means
that whether you make your claim or not, you will get
one time of your cover every year.  Till It
Becomes Five Times of Your Cover.  Plus, there is
also a one-time inbuilt bonus with it.
So, by adding all the bonuses, you can get cover up to six times.
In Neevapa you can get up
to 10 times your cover
with the Booster Plus option.  But this option is
available only with platinum and titanium plants.  To the people below the
age of 35.  In the Gold plan, you can get
cover up to five times only.
You also get an edge lock cover with the Neevapa.
Basically, in all the insurance policies,
your premium increases by 15 to 20% every three to four years.
But in this
your premium will not increase until you claim your policy.  So suppose
if you do not claim your policy for 10 years,
your premium will not increase for 10 years.
Aditya Birla Active On Max
covers you from day one for some chronic diseases like asthma, high BP, high cholesterol, diabetes.  You also get up to
five times cover just like every
other policy with this Super Credit option.
Just To Be Clear Five Times Additional Cover is
available.  One Time of the Cover Every Year.   The
unique point of Bajaj Ali is that
you get maternity benefit in it.  But
if we compare on the basis of overall features then
Bajaj Ali is a little weaker than others.
ICICI is good for those people who want a
really high cover.  It offers you cover of up to 10 CR.  The
second unique point is that this
ICICI cover remains valid even outside India.
So basically it is good for
people who keep on travelling.  Now let us look at
some other benefits of the policies.
First comes the restoration
benefit.  Basically, if you claim your policy, the
insurance company will
restore that amount for the second
time.  In this, you get unlimited restoration benefit from your Niva bank ICICI LBT
Aitya Birla & C.
You get one time restoration benefit in HDFC Ago and Bajaj Alean.
With HDFC Ago you can get cost-effective unlimited
retention benefit.  Like and
add on.  If we talk about wellness benefits, then
basically if you live a healthy lifestyle
then you can get additional benefits from it.
Here are three policies Care
Supreme Niva Bhupa Aditya Birla which are
offering you this benefit.  What they do is they
track your daily steps and overall
fitness.  Ah if we talk about pre and post
hospitalization cover.  Basically,
how many days before admission to the hospital
?  And for
how many days after discharge from the hospital do you get cover?
Overall, it is the same for everyone.  But
in Aditya Birla instead of 60 days you get 90 days
pre hospitalization cover.  And
in Bajaj Allianz instead of 180 days you
get only 90 days post hospitalization cover.  Now We Gonna Talk About the Must Have
Riders.  After that we can conclude our
top three health insurance plans.  Now
friend, there has been a huge change here in the last one year.
Which is the waiting period
for pre-existing illnesses.  Going
forward, IRDAI has said that companies will have to keep
their standard waiting period to a maximum of
3 years.  I would like to
add on thing here that ICICI has another
policy ICICI Elevate in which the
waiting period for pre-existing illness is only
3 years.  Interestingly, it can
drop to two years for six lifestyle
illnesses if you take its Jump Start add-on
for three consecutive years.  So this is
good for people who have pre-
existing illness, for them
ICC Eluveate could be a good choice.  Here
we will talk about two important things
which are non payable
items and OPD cover in which non payable
items are more important.  Non-payable
items are basically consumables like PP
kids, syringes, gloves, masks etc.
Generally, these are not covered by the policy.
Its bill is 15 to 20% of the total bill.
So it is advisable for you to pick a
policy that covers this.  Otherwise,
you will have to pay ₹1 to ₹1.5 lakh from your pocket in a bill of Rs 10 lakh.
Inspite of having a health
insurance plan.  So here there are four policies
HDFC Oct Score, Aitya Birla Activar
Max, Bajaj Health Card C Co and ICICI
Lambar Max Protects, in whose base
policy itself the bill for this non-payable item is
covered.  In other policies,
you have to take an add-on which can
cost five to 10% of your base
premium.  So I mean this is one of the must have
riders in your policy and you should
definitely not miss out on this.  Now we're going to talk about
OPD Rider.  This Is
Like a Good to Have Rider.  Let me tell those who don't know.
So OPD means
those hospital expenses for which you do
not have to be admitted.  Such as doctor
consultation, ECG, blood test
etc.  Now friend, 90% of the expenses
of people are incurred in OPD rather than hospitalization.  Hospitalization expenses are
still rare.  So it is good that if you have
OPD rider, OPD cover.  A Because
you can include your small expenses in it.
And they can save you.
Unfortunately,
this is not included in the base cover of any policy.
For this you will have to take add on rider.
So I mean your
decision cannot change on this basis because
you are not getting this in the base cover in any policy.
Last we will talk about one more thing which
is e consultation.  E-
consultation is normally used in two cases.
Firstly, in cases of chronic diseases,
if there is a cancer patient or a heart disease patient,
then it may be a little difficult for them to go to the hospital.
So in such cases there is e-
consultation which comes in handy.  Second,
if you are taking a policy for an elderly person, then in the
same case, it becomes a
little
difficult for the elderly person to visit the hospital again and again.  So even in such cases, e-
consultation is more beneficial.  So we would want
a policy that also covers e-consultation.
Almost all the
policies here cover e-consultation.
Except Aditya Birla SGSC AGGO,
you also get e-consultation for chronic diseases only.  But
like we discuss, in those cases more
consultation is required.  Now we are
going to compare the premiums of all the policies.  But
before that, I know I am quite sure that you all must be
quite confused as to what is happening brother
?  take what?  Which
policy to take?  So if you want to make your
insurance journey and
insurance process smooth and
avoid all the confusion, get in touch
with Ditto Insurance.  Your
entire insurance journey will be a
breeze.  Do is insurance company
back by Zarora and Do will do all the work for you.
From finding the best policy to
policy issue to making sure you are right on
track with your premiums.  Do everything
absolutely free.  All you have to do is
book a free consultation call with Dato.  As soon as you
book the call, an advisor will be allocated to you within three days
who will guide you completely.
And because this
consultation call is free.  This does not mean
that you will start receiving spam messages.
Unlike Other Companies, Ditto has a
spam-free policy and has a rating of
4.9 out of five on Google Reviews based
on 10,000 plus reviews.  Another special thing is
DTO.  Since Ditto deals with almost all the
insurance on a daily basis they kind of have
a good reputation with them.  And this can be of
great benefit in the claim.  Now
because Team Ditto will process your claim.
It will be relatively stress
free and smoother as well.  And
Ditto will do all this for free.
The link to book a free consultation call with Ditto is
in our description.  Check it out
right now.  Now let us compare the premiums of all the policies once.
This is
for base cover of Rs 50 for a 30 year old
male non smoker living in Delhi.  Here
I want to tell you one thing that the
minimum cover you get in ICICI Max Protect is Rs
1 crore.  So this premium
amount is for the cover of one CR.  All other
policies have a cover of Rs 50 lakh.  A.
Here we have calculated the total amount
of premium and consumables are
also included in it.  Consumables can
form up to 5 to 10% of your base
premium.  So after all this, if I have to
pick my top three then that would be HDFC
Super Secure, Aitya Birla Activ
Max and ICICI LBD Max Protect.  In this
also, if you have any pre-existing illness, then for that
you can consider ICICI Elevate instead of ICICI Max product.   In
which the waiting period for pre-existing illness is
3 years, which can be reduced to
30 days with their Jump
Start add-on.  If you are still confused
or unable to decide on
the best policy for you, get in touch with
Ditto Insurance.  Ditto will find the best policy for you
and that too for free.
The link to book a free consultation call with Detto is
in our description.